egain.net 2015-12-07

# Data Privacy and Security Policy - eGain

### **Introduction**

eGain is committed to the responsible use of information and protecting individual privacy rights on [ **www.egain.com**](http://www.egain.com/) and our platform services. We know you care how information about you is used and shared. This notice describes our privacy policy.

Our Privacy Policy explains:

  * What information we collect
  * How we use that information
  * Information we share
  * User access and choice for the information collected
  * How this information is kept secure

### **Information collected**

We collect information to provide better services to you. We collect information in several ways:

  * **Information you provide us.** For example, we will ask for business contact information such as name, email address and phone number when you register on the site.

  * **Information collected through our platform for eGain’s clients.** eGain collects information on behalf and under the instructions of its clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it collects, processes and stores. eGain’s clients ask for information related to the services they provide you. This information can include personal information such as name, address, contact information (phone, email), gender, date of birth, social security number, and marital status as applicable to the services provided to you. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly.

  * **Information we get from the use of our services.** We log information automatically using log files when our services are used including your usage of these services. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather aggregated demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically collected data to personally identifiable information.Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by eGain and our partners, affiliates, analytics, service provider’s online customer support provider, performance trending. These technologies are used in analysing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. We use cookies for to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference), analytics, for authentication Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

### **How information is used**

We use the information we collect to provide, maintain, improve and protect the services we provide. We also use this information to develop new services and to protect eGain, our clients and users of our services. We also use this to provide more tailored services to you.

We use information collected from cookies and other technologies, like pixel tags, to improve your user experience and the overall quality of our services. For example, by saving your language preferences, we can have our services appear in the language you prefer. One of the products we use to do this on our own services is for data analytics.

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements.  With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name.  If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [publications@egain.com](mailto:publications@egain.com).

When you contact eGain, we keep a record of your communication to help solve any issues you might be facing. We may use your email address to inform you about our services, such as letting you know about upcoming changes or improvements. Out of respect for your privacy, we allow you to opt out of these newsletters by following the unsubscribe directions in them.

eGain processes personal information on our servers in many countries around the world. We may process your personal information on a server located outside the country where you live.

### **Information we share**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as an analytics provider. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our clients.

All information provided to our clients using our platform is controlled by the clients. Refer to their privacy policy on how the information provided is shared with others.

We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or a similar legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, and to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

If eGain is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

### **User access and choice for the information collected**

If your business contact personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove, or deactivate it by making the change on our member information page or by emailing our Customer Support at legal@egain.com. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

eGain has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal information it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the eGains’ client (the data controller). If the client requests eGain to remove the data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

eGain will retain personal data we process on behalf of our clients for as long as needed to provide services to our client. We will retain this personal data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Your personal information will be retained for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking here: <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/> (or if located in the European Union click here: <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

Our blog is managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.

Our site includes links to other web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of eGain. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any web site you visit.

Our site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### **How collected information is kept secure**

eGain adopt has implemented physical, technical, and organizational measures to ensure the security of Personal Data, including the prevention of their alteration, loss, damage, unauthorized processing or access, having regard to the state of the art, the nature and the complexity of the data, and the risks to which they are exposed by virtue of human action or the physical or natural environment. The security of your personal information and our clients’ information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.  When you enter sensitive information (such as your login information) on our service platform, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### **When this Privacy Policy applies**

Our Privacy Policy applies to all of the services offered by eGain. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to services offered by our clients through our platform or to other sites linked from our sites.

### **Compliance with regulatory authorities**

eGain has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [ **TRUSTe’s program requirements**](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) and [ **TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements**](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/trusted-cloud/index.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the English version of the site www.egain.com. The TRUSTe program covers information that may be collected through our platform services (eGain Service Platform, eGain Customer Forums and eGain Support Portal) and does not cover information collected through our eGain Econet and any of our mobile services. The use of information collected through our service are limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged eGain.

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please [contact us](http://www.egain.com/company/contact-us/). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [**TRUSTe here**](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

eGain complies with the U.S.–E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S.–Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland.

eGain has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view eGain’s certification, please visit [**http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/**](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/)

### **Changes to this Policy**

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify users you by means of a notice on our website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### **Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us on the information below.

**eGain**  
1252 Borregas Avenue  
Sunnyvale, CA 94089 USA  
Phone: +1 408-636-4500
